Finding Aid for the Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, 1976-1992
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 24, 11 April 1992, 1 VHS cassette T-120; Title on container: Burchfield Art Center, Buffalo N.Y. USA. North American Music Festival Recorded at Burchfield Art Center (Buffalo, N.Y.). Performers: Haydee Schvartz, piano; Jill Gaylord, mezzo-soprano; Marcelo Maragno, baritone; Timothy Gastle, tenor; Michele Costa, puppets; Paul Schmidt, narrator Durations: 1:15:29 (Box 2, Item 24)
  Contents: Cage, John: Four walls; Satie, Erik: Geneviève de Brabant
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_024_am.mov
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_024_pm.mov
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_024_sc.mov
  DVD or CD disc number 25
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 25, 29 July 1989, 1 VHS cassette unknown length; Title on container: PoMoCoMo - Theory in your ear The performance involved the use of a tracker, Grid Activated Sonar Production, or GASP, worn by dancer Beth Kotecki. Recorded at Articule Gallery, Montreal, Canada. Performers: PoMoCoMo; Beth Kotecki, dancer Durations: 9:01 (Box 2, Item 25)
  Contents: Theory in your ear, a collaborative work by Will Bauer, Rafael Lozano-Hemmer, Andreas Kitzmann, Kim Sawchuck, Steve Gibson, Mark Bell, and others
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_025_am.mov
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_025_pm.mov
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_025_sc.mov
  DVD or CD disc number 26
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 26, 1979 or later, 1 VHS cassette T-120; Title on container: Baker - Chairs Live performance of the work, a theater piece, involving five chairs, a chamber ensemble, a soprano and a speaker/actor. Recorded at unknown location. Performers: Unknown Durations: 18:59 (Box 2, Item 26)
  Contents: Baker, Larry: Chairs
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_026_am.mov
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_026_pm.mov
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_026_sc.mov
  DVD or CD disc number 27
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 27, 1989-1990, 1 VHS cassette T-90; Title on container: Films for music for film: six films by Lawrence F. Brose Recorded at unknown location. Performers: Buffalo New Music Ensemble; Yvar Mikhashoff, piano; Paul Schmidt, narrator; Scott Gray-Vickery, countertenor Durations: 1:10:59 (Box 2, Item 27)
  Contents: Brose: Film for music for film: six films: Everbest, Virgil (Virgil Thomson: Piano sonata no. 2, "Portrait of the artist as a young man" transcription by Mikhashoff) (8:00); Chamnan (music by Brose and Douglas Cohen) (13:00); War songs (poems by Paul Schmidt, music by Mark Bennett); Ryoanji (John Cage) (21:00); Long eyes of earth (Yvar Mikhashoff: Looking through the air from the trilogy Elemental figures, poem "Shaman" by Paul Schmidt) (10:00); Study no. 23 (Conlon Nancarrow)
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_027_am.mov
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_027_pm.mov
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_027_sc.mov
  DVD or CD disc number 28
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 28, undated, 1 Betamax cassette 130; Title on container: Mikhashoff - First session Backup Tape I Audio only from recording session, with multiple takes of some works. Recorded at Bergen (Norway). Performers: Yvar Mikhashoff, piano Durations: 56:00; 55:41 Tape 1 of 4 CTC/NTSC (Box 2, Item 28)
  Contents include: Curran, Alvin: For Cornelius; Rudhyar, Dane: Tango d'Antan; Nichifor, Serban: Tango for Yvar; Foss, Lukas: Tango -- Curriculum vitae. Tango. File 2. Foss, Lukas: Curriculum vitae. Tango; Duckworth, William. Tango voices; Chadabe, Joel: Long ago and far away tango; Johnson: Tango; Ruders, Poul: Tangonetta; Hill, Jackson: Tango no tango; Savaskan, Sinan: Square root impressions with tears; Kondo, Jo: Tango Mnemonic; Genge, Anthony: Tango
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_028_01am.wav; ubmu0001_8_028_02am.wav
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_028_01pm.wav; ubmu0001_8_028_02pm.wav
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_028_01sc.mp3; ubmu0001_8_028_02sc.mp3
  DVD or CD disc number 29-30
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 29, undated, 1 Betamax cassette 130; Title on container: Mikhashoff - First session Tape II Backup Audio only from recording session, with multiple takes of some works. Recorded at Bergen (Norway). Performers: Yvar Mikhashoff, piano Durations: 56:44; 56:15 Tape 2 of 4 (Box 2, Item 29)
  Contents include: Bennett, Richard Rodney: Tango after Syrinx; Rzewski, Frederic: Piano piece no. 4; Bolcom, William: Dead moth tango. File 2. Bolcom: Dead moth tango; Feldman, Morton: Piano
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_029_01am.wav; ubmu0001_8_029_02am.wav
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_029_01pm.wav; ubmu0001_8_029_02pm.wav
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_029_01sc.mp3; ubmu0001_8_029_02sc.mp3
  DVD or CD disc number 31-32
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 30, undated, 1 Betamax cassette 130; Title on container: Mikhashoff - First session master III Audio only from recording session, with multiple takes of some works. Recorded at Bergen (Norway). Performers: Yvar Mikhashoff, piano Durations: 53:15; 48:36 Tape 3 of 4 (Box 2, Item 30)
  Contents include: Griffes, Charles: Preludes no. 1-3; Cage, John: In a landscape; Curran, Alvin: Hope Street Tunnel blues. File 2. Curran, Alvin: Hope Street Tunnel blues; Sahl, Michael: Exiles' café; Foss, Lukas: Solo
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_030_01am.wav; ubmu0001_8_030_02am.wav
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_030_01pm.wav; ubmu0001_8_030_02pm.wav
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_030_01sc.mp3; ubmu0001_8_030_02sc.mp3
  DVD or CD disc number 33-34
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 31, undated, 1 Betamax cassette 130; Title on container: Mikhashoff First session IV Backup Audio only from recording session, with multiple takes of some works. Recorded at Bergen (Norway). Performers: Yvar Mikhashoff, piano Durations: 47:15 Tape 4 of 4 (Box 2, Item 31)
  Contents include: Foss, Lukas: Solo (continued from previous tape)
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_031_01am.wav
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_031_01pm.wav
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_031_01sc.mp3
  DVD or CD disc number 35
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 32, 8 June 1988, 1 VHS cassette T-30; Title on container: Neighbor Music III Recorded at Hallwalls (Buffalo, N.Y.). Performers: Salvatore Andolina, Jerome Simas, clarinet; Ann Laberge, Taci Edwards, flute; Robert Fernandez, Jan Williams, percussion; Stephen L. Mosko, conductor Durations: 32:24 Shot under extreme low-light conditions - begins with silence. (Box 2, Item 32)
  Contents: Cohen, Douglas: Neighbor music III; film by Lawrence F. Brose
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_032_am.mov
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_032_pm.mov
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_032_sc.mov
  DVD or CD disc number 36
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 33, undated, 1 VHS cassette T-30; Title on container: High touch Not reformatted due to subject matter. Recorded at San Francisco. Performers: William Palaskas, speaker (Box 2, Item 33)
  Contents: Dr. William Palaskas: High touch: video about massage technique.
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 34, 11 April 1987, 1 VHS cassette T-30; Title on container: Dan Froot: The Story of Violette Recorded at San Francisco. Performers: Dan Froot, saxophone and speaker Durations: 25:29 (Box 2, Item 34)
  Contents: Froot, Dan: The story of the violette
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_034_am.mov
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_034_pm.mov
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_034_sc.mov
  DVD or CD disc number 37
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 35, 12 June 1988, 1 VHS cassette E-120; Title on container: Listahatid 1988: Norraeni kvartettinn Recorded at Bústaðakirkju, Reykjavik, Iceland. Performers: Norraeni kvartettinn: Einar Jóhannesson, clarinet; Joseph Fung, guitar; Áskell Másson, Roger Carlsson, percussion Durations: 1:23:50 Listahatid I Reykjavik 4-19 June 1988 (Box 2, Item 35)
  Contents: Másson, Áskell: Fantasia um kinverskt; Hauksson, Thorstein: Tokkata f. gitar; Másson, Áskell: Impromptu f. fjórar handtrommur; Heininen, Paavo: Discantus II f. klarinett; Nørgaard, Per: Waves, f. slagverk; Másson, Áskell: Divertimento f. kvartett; Fung: Choreographic poems, f. kvartett
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_035_am.mov
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_035_pm.mov
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_035_sc.mov
  DVD or CD disc number 38
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 36, 17 February 1989, 1 VHS cassette T-120; Title on container: Aki Takahashi New ears series VII Recorded at Yokohama (Japan). Performers: Aki Takahashi, Yvar Mikhashoff, piano; others Durations: 1:24:19 Very dark (Box 2, Item 36)
  Contents include performances of George Brecht: Drip music; John Cage: Music for (Four); Sylvano Bussotti: Gran duo; Mieko Shiomi: A trick of time Part II
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_036_am.mov
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_036_pm.mov
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_036_sc.mov
  DVD or CD disc number 39
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 37, 1989?, 1 VHS cassette unknown length; Title on container: Satie Sports et divertissements The tape is a recording from a performance of Satie's Sports et divertissements broadcast on Japanese television featuring a "Jan-Paulo"; with Japanese subtitles. Recorded at Japan. Performers: Unknown Durations: 58:59 (Box 2, Item 37)
  Contents: Satie, Erik: Sports et divertissements
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_037_am.mov
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_037_pm.mov
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_037_sc.mov
  DVD or CD disc number 40
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 38, 1986, 1 VHS cassette E-120; Title on container: West Coast Story Episode 1: Frontiers of New Music Film produced by Eva Soltes and directed by Michael McIntyre for BBC, a three-part program about California composers. BBC's summary: This film tells the story of the development of west coast music in this century, against the background of the Californian landscape, the Asian communities of San Francisco and the cybernetic paradise of Silicon valley. Recorded at Multiple locations. Performers: John Chowning, Garrett Bowles, Rinde Eckert, Ron George, Jerry Goldsmith, Joe Kubera, Yvar Mikhashoff, Danlee Mitchell, Doren Nelson, Pauline Oliveros, Steve Reich, Roger Reynolds, Dave Whittaker; directed by Michael Macintyre Durations: 1:15:09 (Box 2, Item 38)
  Contents: With contributions from John Cage, Terry Riley, John Adams, Lou Harrison, Frank Zappa, Charles Amirkhanian, Robert Erickson, Paul Dresher, Daniel Lentz, and Morton Subotnick
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_038_am.mov
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_038_pm.mov
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_038_sc.mov
  DVD or CD disc number 41
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 39, July 1990, 1 VHS cassette T-60; Title on container: Amnon Wolman’s Concerto for piano, piano[s] and orchestra Recorded at Banff (Alberta, Canada). Performers: Anthony De Mare, piano; Banff Chamber Players; Michael Century, conductor Durations: 31:28 (Box 2, Item 39)
  Contents: Wolman, Amnon: Concerto for piano, pianos, and orchestra (pianist plays seven Disklaviers)
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_039_am.mov
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_039_pm.mov
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_039_sc.mov
  DVD or CD disc number 42
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 40, 1987?, 1 VHS cassette E-120; Title on container: VOX - Festspillene A film by NRK (Norsk rikskringkasting AS - Norwegian Broadcasting Company) containing excerpts from the festival, Bergen 1987. Recorded at Bergen (Norway). Performers: Performers include Yvar Mikhashoff, piano; Knut Skram, Benedicte Adrian, Ingrid Bjornov, singers; Daniel Bohr, festival director Durations: 50:29 (Box 2, Item 40)
  Contents include John Cage's Perpetual tango, African drumming, and more
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_040_am.mov
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_040_pm.mov
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_040_sc.mov
  DVD or CD disc number 43
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
Music--20th century; Piano music
Genres
videotapes; videocassettes; sound recordings; musical performances
Associated Material
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
Yvar Mikhashoff Archive
The Yvar Mikhashoff Archive consists of the following separate components. Descriptions can be found at the page for the Yvar Mikhashoff Archive at
http://library.buffalo.edu/music/special-materials/yvar-mikhashoff/
:
Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Compositions
Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Transcriptions
Yvar Mikhashoff Photograph Collection
Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Tangos
Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Sound Recordings
Yvar Mikhashoff Cassette Collection
Yvar Mikhashoff Slide Collection